# **Deepak Kumar**

# Lead UI/Front-end Engineer

# [5+ years of Experience]

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Looking for a position as Lead UI/Front-end Engineer, where I could create digital magic and user experience to the next level.

I have a total of 5+ years of experience in UI Engineering and Front-end Development, proficiency in the latest front-end technology with new frameworks for fully responsive web UI /Front-end development.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Onato, Bengaluru Karnataka

— Lead UI/Frontend Engineer (full-time)

Oct 2021 - Present

## Cashfree Payments India Pvt. Ltd., Bengaluru Karnataka

— Senior UI *Developer* (full-time - 2 years 2 months)

July 2019 – September 2021

# MVigyan Consulting Private Limited, Noida UP

— Senior UI Engineer (full-time - 1 year 2 months)

February 2018 - March 2019

# Astrotalk (Codeyeti Software Solutions Pvt. Ltd.), Noida UP

— UI Developer (full-time - 1 year 4 months)

August 2016 - December 2017

#### **EDUCATION**

**Dr. A.P.J. Abdul Kalam Technical University,** Lucknow UP — *B.Tech (Computer Science & Engg.)* 2011 - 2015

St.G.N. Inter Clg. , Firozabad UP — Intermediate (*PCM*) - 2010

S.V.M., Farrukhabad UP — High-school - 2008

#### **SUMMARY OF SKILLS**

#### **CONTACT**

+91-8285580121

#### **EMAIL**

dkshakya2014@gmail.com

#### **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

- \* ReactJS
- \* NextJS,GatsBy,GraphQL
- \* JavaScript (ES6),OOJS
- \* Typescript
- \* HTML5
- \* CSS3, Tailwind CSS
- \* Sass (CSS Preprocessor)
- \* Bootstrap 3/4, Material UI
- \* SPA, PWA, RWD
- \* PSD to HTML/wordpress
- \* Canvas & SVG, D3.js, Chart.js
- \* version Control(Git)

#### **TOOLS & TECH**

- \* Node.js,NPM,webpack,gulp
- \* Browser Developer Tool
- \* Docker/FileZilla/Xampp
- \* Sublime text/visual Code
- \* AWS(S3,EC2),Cpanel,FTP
- \* bitbucket/Gitlab/Github
- \* Sketch, Figma, Photoshop
- \* Zeplin,anima,invision
- \* Jira (Agile & kanban),

#### **PERSONAL DETAIL**

- \* DOB- 01-01-1993
- \* Marital Status single
- \* Location -Bengaluru

- \* Proficiency in UI/Front-end Development with ReactJS, HTML, CSS, and fully responsive web UI development.
- \* Hands-on experience of client-side scripting and JavaScript frameworks and library jQuery, ReactJS & frameworks like NextJS, Gatsby.
- \* Proficient understanding of cross-browser compatibility issues and ways to work around them and code versioning tools, such as Git.
- \* Good understanding of SEO principles and ensuring that application will adhere to them.
- \* Familiarity with browser testing and debugging.
- \* Working knowledge with CSS preprocessors SASS/LESS and CSS organization methodologies BEM, OOCSS, SMACSS.
- \* Experience in developing complex, high-traffic Web Applications.

#### **ROLE & RESPONSIBILITIES**

- \*handle the team to help in technical deliverables. Mentor junior Devs for design and proper coding practices.
- \* Translate designs to front-end code, develop new user-facing features.
- \* Build reusable react component-based code and libraries for future use.
- \* Write code, Unit tests, complete programming and perform the testing and debugging of moderately complex features following detailed specifications.
- \* Design solution for moderately complex features.
- \* Optimize application for maximum speed and scalability and SEO.
- \* Work closely with Product Managers, UX designers and back-end engineers to implement front-end solutions.
- \* Involved in unit testing while developing the application, thereby reducing the number of reworks and miscalculations at the development phase itself.

#### **RECENT LIVE PROJECTS**

## Cashfree Merchant Dashboard

-https://merchant.cashfree.com

Skills used:-ReactJS, HTML5, CSS3, semanticUI, sass, RWD

Cashfree (Website )— cashfree.com

Skills used: PHP, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, RWD

Uniacco ( Portal Student accommodation ) — Uniacco.com

Skills used:-Next.js, React.js, Redux, HTML5, SCSS, Bootstrap, RWD

Unicred — <a href="https://unicreds.com">https://unicreds.com</a>

Skills used:-Next.js, React.js, Redux, HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, RWD

#### PREFERED LOCATION

\* Bengaluru

#### **FOCUSING ON**

\* New Web Technologies

#### **PERSONAL & SOFT SKILLS**

- \* Self-motivation & Positivity
- \* Interpersonal Skill
- \* Communication
- \* Time Management
- \* Leadership
- \* Problem Solving

#### **INTERESTS & HOBBIES**

- \* watching movies
- \* Listing music

### **LANGUAGES**

\* English \* Hindi

#### **ONLINE PORTFOLIO / PROFILE**

- \* https://shakyadeep.online
- \* Github dkshakva17

#### **LINKEDIN**

deepak-kumar-5bb50298